## Konstantin Tenman

Software Engineer London, United Kingdom

+447487553781konstantin@tenman.ee https://github.com/ktenman https://www.linkedin.com/in/ktenman

### PROFILE

Self-motivated software developer with six years of experience in the field and four years of experience in Java development. Motivated to participate as a team player and develop well-tested applications using a continuous delivery approach. I highly enjoy carrying out profound research and learning about new technologies, alongside looking for ways to improve my work.

### Programming Skills

• Languages: Java, TypeScript Technologies: Spring Framework, Angular, Hibernate, Junit, Mockito

• Tools: AWS, PostgreSQL, Docker, Git, Jenkins, Maven, IntelliJ, Redis

### EXPERIENCE

• Monese London, United Kingdom Mar 2019 - Present Software Engineer

- Reduced costs by systematically working to improve software performance and decrease operating costs. For one application, its monthly operating cost was decreased by 50%.
- Increased revenue by doggedly identifying and fixing production issues. In one case, pursuing a solution for a single customer led to identifying a significant gap in profit.
- Pricing: Led research on breaking a monolithic application into single responsibility micro-services. Refactored and developed the pricing structure of the system. Delivered business priorities by completing a new annual pricing functionality on-time and without any significant issues.
- Joint Accounts: Designed and developed the main logic around the Joint Accounts feature.

• Monese Tallinn, Estonia Software Engineer Oct 2017 - Mar 2019

- Smart Transactions: Improved scalability of micro-services by separating the read and write operation of the database. Gradually migrated 120M payments to a new queue-based Java micro-service. Decreased average response time from 60ms to 5ms. Researched and introduced the new Angular 5 framework for internal tooling. Helped improve seamless deployment in Amazon AWS.
- Recurring Payments: Designed and developed a micro-service with a test coverage of up to 80%.
- o Tools: Java 8-11, Angular, TypeScript, Grails, Scala, Docker, Amazon AWS, PostgreSQL, Spring Boot, Google API, Mockito, Junit, Redis, AWS, CloudWatch, New Relic, Jenkins, Git, Intellij, Groovy, Testcontainers, Maven, Liquibase, Bootstrap, macOS

• Codeborne Tallinn, Estonia Software Developer Apr 2017 - Oct 2017

- - Developed a responsive internet banking website for desktop and mobile platforms.

• Developed an internet banking website now used by 2M customers.

o Tools: Java 8, RiotJS, Selenium, Mockito, TDD, Intellij, Agile, extreme programming, Play! Framework, Ubuntu

• Knowit Tallinn, Estonia Software Developer Jun 2016 - Apr 2017

o Developed a full-stack, web-based application where users create services and search for them through Google Maps.

• Technologies: AngularJS, Java 8, Docker, Spring Boot, Hibernate, JHipster, Sass, CSS3, HTML5, Protractor, Maven, Liquibase, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, Ubuntu, Git

# **EDUCATION**

Tallinn University Estonia 2014 - 2017